Guide to the Homophobia Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Homophobia collection
1961-1989
1980-1989
MS 1852
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The collection includes assorted publications documenting homophobia in the United States.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Larry Kramer Initiative Executive Coordinator, 2004-2005. Transferred from the Librarian for Gay and Lesbian Studies, 2007. Transferred from the LGBT Co-Op, 2009.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by author or title when author is unknown.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes assorted publications documenting homophobia in the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Homophobia -- United States; Homosexuality -- United States; LGBTQ resource
- Inventory
  - Ad Hoc Gay Committee, A New Danger From the Religious Right-Wing: the rise in anti-Gay religious street activity in our communities, 1980 March 15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - All-Peoples Congress/All Family Coalition, Say NO to Falwell, Schlafly, & Right Wing Violence! [flyer announcing a rally/celebration of unity], 1984 July 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Anita Bryant Ministries: When the homosexuals burn the Holy Bible in public...how can I stand by silently [mailer], undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clymer, R. Swinburne, America's Betrayal, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - de Valk, Alphonse, Homosexuality: The Gay Drive for Acceptance [reprint, originally published 1976 Mar-Apr], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Deep Backgrounder, vol. 1, #1, Circa 1982 May/June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dolan, John T. (Terry) and Greg Fossedal, Reagan: A Record of Achievement [publisher's proof copy], 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Gay Radio Collective and Jim Keppner, Quotations from Chief Ed, or: Six Years with Foot-in-Mouth Disease [about Edward M. Davis, chief of police in Los Angeles], 1976 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Homosexuality and Citizenship in Florida [Florida Legislative Investigation Committee], 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Institute for the Scientific Investigation of Sexuality
    - Criminality, Social Disruption and Homosexuality, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Homosexuality and the AIDS threat to the nation's blood supply, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Homosexuality: Everybody's Problem, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Medical Aspects of Homosexuality, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - What Causes Homosexuality and Can It Be Cured?, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - What Homosexuals Do (Its More Than Merely Disgusting), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Child Molestation and Homosexuality, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Psychology of Homosexuality, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Murder, Violence and Homosexuality, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - LaHaye, Tim, A Christian View of Radical Sex Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Love in Action International, A Christ-Centered Way Out of Homosexuality, [pamphlet], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Message to Anti-Gay Scum--Prepare to Shed Blood!!!, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - NS Mobilizer, Official publication of the National Socialist League, Vol. II-IV, 1976 January-1978 Winter (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Segrest, Mab and Leonard Zeskind, Quarantines and Death: The Far Right's Homophobic Agenda, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sutton, Bob, Homosexuality, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Swaggart, Jimmy, Homosexuality: Its Cause and Its Cure, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Roses: the message of Our Lady & Our Lord to Veronica Lueken, 1985 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Homosexuality, Speaking the Truth in Love," 3 copies, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)